

□ (+91) 7003666272 | ■ paulashis0013@gmail.com | □ ashis0013 | □ ashis-paul-173479150 | ☎ Ashis Paul

About

Full stack developer with over 1.5 years of experience in building software solution at pace and at scale. Passionate in using declarative paradigm. As a dedicated problem solver I have experience of working in Backend Development, Android Development and Frontend Web Development. Skilled in Microservices, Distributed Systems, Go, Kotlin, Amazon Web Service, Low Level Design, Algorithm, Native Android Development, Data Structure.

Skills

Technical Skills Micro services Distributed Systems AWS LLD React Mobile Development **Programming Languages** Go Kotlin (JVM) Typescript Python

Soft Skills Agile development Problem solving Multitasking Teamwork Mentoring

Experiences _____

Compass Hyderabad, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2021 - Jan. 2023

- Contributing to gRPC backend services responsible for generating insights for compass listings. Improved test coverage of the service codebase from 10% to 86%. Currently contributing to new features to gather openhouse and email-campaign insights.
- Developed a backend microservice to gather insights on the third party support ticketing service, which helped product team to identify the problem areas in customer support and helped the support team to reduce the resolution time by 25%.
- Delivered frontend features using React to enhance article search used in the compass Support and Onboarding System.
- Worked with CRM and TM Android team and **delivered crucial features** such as Client Dashboard, Contact Import, Household Support which are being used by over 10 thousands compass agents.
- Fixed over 10 production crashes during on-call duty and refactored(LLD) over 5000 lines of code on the Android codebase.

Microsoft Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

May. 2020 - Jul. 2020

- Developed a pClick model to predict clickability of bing ads from global market data using Aether and Scope.
- Studied impact of the global model on the large and small markets where the global model performed as good (less by 0.01%) as market specific models.

Education

Jadavpur University

Kolkata - 700032 BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING Aug. 2017 - Jun. 2021

CGPA: 8 91/10 First Class Honours

Chatra Nandalal Institution Serampore, Hooghly - 712204

Mar. 2015 - May. 2017 HIGHER SECONDARY

Percentage: 93.4%

Projects_

Inverted Bell-Curve based Ensemble of Deep Learning Models

PYTHON{PYTORCH} Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Utilized the inverted Gaussian function to formulate a method of weighted average to combine the confidence scores from clas-
- Implemented a deep ensemble using the proposed method as combinator function to detect COVID from 3000 chest x-ray images and achieved 99% accuracy.

SVM based Deep Ensemble for Music Symbol Recognition

PYTHON{PYTORCH, SKLEARN} Feb. 2021 - Mar. 2021

- Used fine-tuning of imagenet pretrained models on music symbol datasets to build recognizer model.
- Applied support vector machine as a ensemble combinator to combine Transfer Learning models at score level.